Daniel Precioso

daniprec.github.io | LinkedIn | GitHub | ResearchGate

Location: Madrid, Spain Email: daniel.precioso@uca.es ORCID: 0000-0003-3836-1429

DATA SCIENTIST

I am a highly skilled data scientist with over 5 years of experience in machine learning and Python. With a passion for learning and growth, I am a highly motivated and proactive individual who enjoys working collaboratively to solve complex problems. My strong team work skills and ability to communicate effectively enable me to contribute to successful project outcomes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Python, Matlab, R

Libraries : NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, TensorFlow

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Github

Academic Tools: Latex

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Sep 2022 - Present Komorebi Al Madrid, Spain

- Data cleaning, manipulation and visualization.
- · Design, train and deployment of machine learning and deep learning models with scikit-learn, including GB and CNN.
- Development of a dashboard to guide industrial decision making with Streamlit.

Predoctoral Research Staff

Sep 2019 - Aug 2022 University of Cádiz Cádiz, Spain

- Collaboration with various industrial partners to conduct cutting-edge research in healthcare, energy and blue economy.
- Presentation of research findings to both technical and non-technical audiences.
- Publication of research papers in peer-reviewed journals.

Junior Data Scientist

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 Foqum Madrid, Spain

EDUCATION

Sep 2019 – Present <i>Cádiz, Spain</i>
Sep 2018 – Jul 2019 <i>Madrid, Spain</i>
Sep 2014 – Jul 2018 Madrid, Spain

NeoCam

Machine Learning, Python

- We used the Luxonis OAK-D smart camera to build a contactless monitoring system for newborn babies.
- The proposed solution combined computer vision, machine learning, edge computing, cloud computing and Internet of things.
- NeoCam project was awarded the second prize in the international final of, in which over 1400 teams participated.

Smart Shipping

Data Science, Python

- Our goal was to optimize marine shipping routes, by using real time information of ocean currents, wind and waves.
- Smart Shipping project was awarded the second prize in the international final of <u>Ocean Hackathon 2021</u>, hosted by Campus Mondiale de la Mer in Brest (France).

Fly Your Satellite

Physics, Matlab

- Our goal was to optimize marine shipping routes, by using real time information of ocean currents, wind and waves.
- Smart Shipping project was awarded the second prize in the international final of <u>Ocean Hackathon 2021</u>, hosted by Campus Mondiale de la Mer in Brest (France).

CERTIFICATIONS

- Machine learning in Python with scikit-learn (France Université Numérique)
- <u>TensorFlow in Practice Specialization</u> (Coursera)
- Applied Social Network Analysis in Python (Coursera)
- Applied Machine Learning in Python (Coursera)
- Applied Text Mining in Python (Coursera)
- Introduction to Data Science in Python (Coursera)

PUBLICATIONS

Neocam